Obinna Henry Nwamuo

Airdrie, AB | 236-858-5838 henrynwamuo@gmail.com

Summary

Hard-working HVAC/R Master Service Technician with 12+ years of experience, offering proven history in managing residential, commercial and industrial HVAC needs with skillful and efficient repairs. Have installed 128 home systems, most as lead tech. Handled 800+ service calls, bulding strong customer relationships and growing annual revenue by 10%

Experience

McHenry Refrigeration Company | Nigeria, Lagos

Owner and Head HVAC and Refrigeration Technician/Contractor | 05/2023 - Present

- * Directed a team of 2 HVAC/R techs on designing, fabrication and installation of various sizes and capacities of walk-in cold storage in busy frozen food business.
- * Performed over 78 full hermetic and semi-hermetic condensing units and their indoor evaporators, using brands like Copeland, Bitzer, Carrier (Carlyle) Danfoss (Maneurope) etc, most on 2,000+ sq/ft structures.
- * Handled over 850 service calls of cold storage compressor overhauling and repairs, spare parts replacements with 97% customer satisfaction.
- * Sales and distribution of HVAC/R equipments eg chiller condensing units and evaporators, semi-hermetic and hermetic, screw, scroll and belt drive compressors (With brands like Copeland, York, Bitzer, Carrier, Danfoss, Panasonic, Daikin) condensing units etc.
- * Residential and Commercial Air-conditioning system services such as refrigerant gas and compressor replacements, cleaning, disassembling and reassembling of AC systems.
- * Assembled air ducts, pipes, discharge valves and flues to central heating and cooling equipment.

Natural Basket Nigeria Limited | Nigeria, Lagos

Freelance HVAC and Refrigeration Technician | 03/2019 - 04/2020

- * Conducted preventative maintenance and troubleshoot HVAC/R systems to identify and resolve issues.
- * Performed routine inspections and provide recommendations for equipment upgrades and replacements.
- * Ensured compliance with safety regulations and company policies.
- * Documented all service work, including time and materials used, in a detailed and accurate manner for billing and record-keeping purposes.

IKN Technical Services Ltd. | Nigeria, Lagos

HVAC-R/Sheet Metal Apprentice and Sales Representative | 03/2014 - 01/2019

- * Assisted with install of HVAC system in 5,000 sq/ft animal shelter.
- * Commended 4 times by manager for willingness to handle any dirty job.
- * Used sales skills to sell new products and systems to customers.
- * Initiated and nurtured impactful relationships with customers to cultivate loyalty

Lafarge Nigeria | Nigeria, Aba

Construction Worker | 03/2010 - 12/2013

- * Worked with more knowledgeable professionals to grow understanding of principles and construction standards.
- * Installed drywall, flooring and other interior finishes to create finished and functional living and work spaces.
- * Assisted in constructing roads, bridges and other infrastructure projects to respond to economic, fiscal and environmental changes.
- * Assembled and disassembled scaffolding and ladders to guarantee safety of workers while performing tasks at heights.
- * Brought materials and tools from trucks and storage facilities to work site locations and organized for expected needs.

Skills

Heavy Equipment Operation, Piping Layout and Assembly, Blueprint Reading, CNC Machine Operation, HVAC/R Systems Expertise, Maintenance, Construction Management, Organization and Time Management, Installation and Repair, Teamwork and Collaboration, Excellent Written and Verbal Communication, Creatively Thinking, Microsoft word

Education

Ugo Comprehensive Secondary School | Aba, Nigeria General Studies | 09/2009

Certificates

HVAC/R Certified - Federal Ministry of Labour and Employment Nigeria (Certificate of Competence) 2017 - 2022

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/obinnahenrynwamuo